<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Murugesh Marvel</title>
    <description>My Personal Blog</description>
    <link>http://localhost:3000/</link>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:3000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
    <pubDate>Wed, 18 Apr 2018 14:54:26 +0530</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 18 Apr 2018 14:54:26 +0530</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v3.5.1</generator>
    
      <item>
        <title>Machine Learning - Explained</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Its easy to guess from the name &lt;strong&gt;Machine Learning&lt;/strong&gt;, which implies some process related to learning process of machines. And Nowdays people are really curious to learn Machine learning by witnessing the changes that it bought. This blog is not for some programming geeks or for people with computer science background. I will try my best to explain this concept as low as possible.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Machine learning is field in Artificial Intelligence which allow machines to learn from the experience(data) rather than being hard-coded.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;what-is-learning-&quot;&gt;What is Learning ?&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The most easy way to grap the learning concept without steping to the cognitive science is by considering some real-time example. Consider a Scenario, you got a new job and you are leaving to the new-office from your house for the first time. Possibly, you will take some long time for the first(let the time be &lt;strong&gt;x&lt;/strong&gt;). Then eventually after some days the time for you to reach office from your home will definitely be less than the initial time &lt;strong&gt;x&lt;/strong&gt;. What actually happened in the meanwhile is that you learned some optimal routes for your office with several experience over several days. Cool!, hope the following example helped you in getting to know about learning and also from this example you will get to know that learning happens only with experience.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;working-machine&quot;&gt;Working Machine&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The word Machines literally means some system designed to do some tasks, it may be a robot, a Personal Computer, Car,.etc. The machines that operates by Mechanical Power are soo limited and narrowed in their operation, its just some movements of some pullies and lever inside it due to some physical principles and works on why it was designed. And in contrast, the electronical Machines had came into existance or been fused with the Mechanical ones by promising both automation and optimization of the task it meant to work. But, how this electronical system know how to operate a task?. Well there is where our Programming comes into play. &lt;strong&gt;Progamming&lt;/strong&gt; actually got many sides, but the core objective is to solve a problem. Whether it is C, C++, Embedded C, Java, Javascipt, Python, Ruby, Go, Lua,..whatever that language is, its just been used to solve a problem with different approach and design. You can refer this &lt;img src=&quot;&quot; alt=&quot;link&quot; /&gt; to know more on programming and programming languages.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;rule-based-programming&quot;&gt;Rule Based Programming&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Well I told you we are avoiding machine being hard-coded by Machine Learning. Rule based programming is some that is hard-coded. Take an example Scenario, you have a problem of finding the price of the water bottle that varies on their quantity. This problem can we easily solved given the Price list with respect to Litres. Then just make a program with if condition like the following.(following example is in the python syntax)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;language-python&quot;&gt;if (litre == 1):
  price = 20
elif (litre == 2):
  price = 40
elif (litre == 3):
  price = 60
elif (litre == 4):
  price = 80
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Do Machines Really have to Learn?&lt;/strong&gt; - If you want your machine to assist you in a better possible way than the rules based thing, you have to let your machine to learn, letting it to know your data for optimising its assistance.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 08 Jan 2018 00:00:00 +0530</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:3000/blog/2018/Machine-Learning-Explained/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:3000/blog/2018/Machine-Learning-Explained/</guid>
        
        
        <category>General</category>
        
        <category>Machine_learning</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Community for AI people on Tamilnadu</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Tamilnadu is always known for its cultural heritage and people here are always a kind of crazy guys in different aspects. Maybe on current scenario, the unstable government is also on the top of list, probably we can skip this now. But to be honest people here refuse to adapt to new technologies, Artificial Intelligence is not an exception. I am an AI developer specialized in Computer vision, contributing for startups and open-source projects, I am an AI enthusiast from my high school days and a practitioner in my college days and one of the consequence is that my facebook, twitter, linkedin,..etc updates are fully filled with things related to AI, AGI, Cognitive Science, Singularity,.. and several other crazy pieces of stuff. When I was about to decide my future step on AI after finishing my undergrad degree, many people (probably everyone whom I talked) recommended me to go for my masters in a reputable college possibly abroad but at that time I should had thought why? instead, I conventionally thought How can I able to get to those colleges, what should I be having in my SOP?..etc. I had been decided to use rest 1 year in my college to learn several things in the field, build a network with people in this domain. I approached several professors, the industrial people working on AI, but where I ended up is connecting through several researchers in AI through facebook. Thanks to several FB friends, blogs, tutorials,.. I developed a good amount of knowledge and skill set to work in AI and I am able to follow updates easily. But as people say, the world suddenly seems to be changed when you come out from college, yeah it happened for me after I joined a startup in Chennai and began to adapt to the modern-tech life in Chennai. Started to attend several meetups, discussions, gatherings etc..But even in Chennai, the tech place of Tamilnadu, the paradise for startups,..the beauty of AI and its potential was and is still not understood. People here are just been fascinated by AI and want to exploit AI to maximize their profit which is not bad but is like using rolls Royce to garbage carrier. but what about others who are from the rural side of Tamilnadu, even students from several part of Chennai have no idea what the AI all about and how people around the world are adapting to it. There are still many Ramanujan been born in Tamilnadu and due to lack of awareness and guidance, they stay where they are and are unable to realize their potential and that of AI(mostly imposed by society). There are several engineering students who don’t know the fundamentals mathematics and even if they knew they lacking with the practical application, even I was like this once before but learning statistical principles, coding programs to gather and clean data, developing machine learning model, neural networks, optimising it,..etc. opened several possibilities of learning algebra, differential calculus in real life. And parallel, Intelligence system can help you in automating numerous routine and repeated things and saves several.hours which can be put into more useful things . People around the world had already adapted to these technologies and we are still waiting for big giants to do pull these things to us once its out-dated. There are still many Chennai based startups working on several disrupting technologies in the aim of changing the place we live, but society here fails to motivate them and the most saddest thing is that people don’t even understand what they are working on. 
Now I clearly understand that there is no scarcity of people working on AI in Chennai but thing is that they are scattered and the flow of knowledge is obstructed due to lack of a proper channel for discourse. And moreover, Chennai is not Tamilnadu, its a small portion of it and there are still several districts where both crazy and coolest brains can be found. Sorry for putting several boring words, let me be precise, I strictly believe Artificial Intelligence is going to power the evolution of human race at an unprecedented rate n future and as every state has the rights in cherishing the outcomes they also have the responsibility in contributing to it, not all the things should be done by people of silicon valley or people acquired by silicon valley. I cannot say that I will be able to push the boundaries of technology in my state but I am gonna try as hell to do so. who knows, maybe if we join hands and work together we will be able to do it. Also, I need to add that we (Murugesh, Suriyadeepan, Syed, Aquid &amp;amp; Selva) with help of several other friends started a Community for the purpose that I stated before and named it as “TN-AI Guild”. We had also Inaugurated this community in two main districts of TN namely Chennai &amp;amp; Coimbatore also had a meetup for discussing “Capsule Network”. Several AI-Startups and Professionals are supporting us a lot on our mission. We have people good in domain expertise, shining in their own field, cool and awesome people on advisory board, yet we need some active people on organizing things. We are currently in bootstrapping stage yet to fix things and plan.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2018 00:00:00 +0530</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:3000/blog/2018/Community-for-AI-People-on-Tamilnadu/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:3000/blog/2018/Community-for-AI-People-on-Tamilnadu/</guid>
        
        
        <category>TN-AI</category>
        
        <category>General</category>
        
        <category>Artificial_Intelligence</category>
        
        <category>Tamilnadu</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Working With GIT</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;If you are a software developer, its mandatory to know what &lt;strong&gt;git&lt;/strong&gt; is. I hope this page will make you understand what git and how it will be useful to you. Before getting into practical tutorial of GIT, Let me first get you with some boring histroy and other content. When Linus Torvald was developing “Linux”, he find very difficult to manage several things like different versions of release, collaborators for the projects,.. and more. So he thought of making a framework that can address this problem. After on, he came up with a solution and named that with his behavior &lt;strong&gt;GIT&lt;/strong&gt; (git means unpleasant man). And later on several web platform emerged to help developers to help in collaboration, version control and maintaining their projects with help of git. (Eg: github, gitlab..etc..).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This tutorial will make you in learning GIT in basics and intermediate level for working on open source projects and contributing to some libraries,..etc. There are 2 main prerequisites before starting the tutorial.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt; To have a Github account. https://github.com/join &lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt; To install git in your working system. https://git-scm.com/book/en/v2/Getting-Started-Installing-Git &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To check whether GIT is installed in your system, type&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;git –version
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;and make sure the terminal gives you the version number of the git installed (Like shown in the image below)&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;/images/working_with_git/git_version.png&quot; alt=&quot;git version&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are two ways in starting a Github project.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;1-creating-a-new-repository-in-github-and-cloning-it-in-your-local-system&quot;&gt;1. Creating a new repository in Github and Cloning it in your local system.&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Initially for creating a git project, login into your Github account and visit to this link. You will be asked for details for your projects as shown in the below image.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/working_with_git/new_repo.png&quot; alt=&quot;git cloning link&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The details to be filled are as follows:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt; &lt;bold&gt;Repository Name :&lt;/bold&gt; Name of your repository with which your project will be reffered.&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt; Description: A short description of your project which will let other developer to look into your project.&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt; Public (or) Private: You can select any one of this option. If you make your repository as Public, it will visible to all developers and anyone can contribute for your repository. The other option is making your repository Private, my doing this you can prevent people to view your repository and codes but you have to pay for making your repository as Private one. If you are a student, you can try for Github Student Developer Pack [https://education.github.com/pack] by which you can make your repository Private without paying money and also you get more free goodies with it.&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt; Initialize your Repository with a README: README.md is one the important file for project. This file projects what exactly your project is?. Developing a good README.md file will add more value to your repository. You can refer this post for learning how to develope a cool README.md file.&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt; Adding .gitignore file: This file tell git to not include some files to the remote repository. We will cover .gitignore in the next part of this tutorial. &lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt; Adding License file: If you work on a really serious project, and to protect your codes being used by other or commercial purpose,..etc.you can add a license file for your repository. There are several Types of license that can be applied for your project depending on its type, you can refer those types in this site.&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After providing relevant details you can click “Create Repository” for creating your repository.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Then to add working files and codes of your project to your repository, you need to clone your repository in your local system.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For cloning a repository, you need to get the https link of your project as shown in the below image.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/working_with_git/cloning_link.png&quot; alt=&quot;git cloning link&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After copying the Https link, go to your terminal and type&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;git clone &amp;lt;Https Link&amp;gt;
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;as shown in the image below&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/working_with_git/clone_repo.png&quot; alt=&quot;git cloning repo&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Then if you get into the repository folder newly created, you can see the README.md for your repository as show in the below image.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/working_with_git/clone_repo.png&quot; alt=&quot;git cloning repo&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Great, we had successfully cloned our repository in our local System and further we can add or change files in the repository which we will discuss after after discussing on the second method of starting a Github Project.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;2-creating-local-project-folder-and-link-with-the-github-repository&quot;&gt;2. Creating local project folder and link with the github repository.&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Initially creat a Github repository as we done in the first step. Then create a new folder in your local system. Now the folder you had created is just a normal folder but you need a git supported folder for linking to your repository. So you can initialise git in the particular folder using the following command after getting into the main project folder.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;git init
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I had created a folder name “git_tutorial” and initialised git in that folder as shown in the below image&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/working_with_git/git_init.png&quot; alt=&quot;git init&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now this folder is just empty one, let we link remote repository with this folder using the following command&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;git remote add origin &amp;lt;https link&amp;gt;
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The https link is the link of your github repository which is needed to be linked. The origin refers to the local folder. Even after adding the remote repository the files are not update. So for updating the files the following command is used.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;git pull origin master
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The master here refers to the branch name of the remote repository.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/working_with_git/git_pull.png&quot; alt=&quot;git pull&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Great, We had successfully linked our local project folder with the remote repository and pulled the README.md file from our repository.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now let us start making some changes in the README.md file push back to the repository.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Let me some lines to the README.md file in the local project folder. Then this changes will be shown only in the local file and not in the remote file. For updating this change to the remote repository. We have some series of steps to be followed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/working_with_git/change1.png&quot; alt=&quot;git change1&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After changing the file, type the following command in the terminal&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;git status
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Then you will see the file name that is been change had been marked in red color. Further we add the file to our stack for committing using the following command.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;git add README.md
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In case if you change multiple file and want to add all the file, you can use the following command.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;git add .
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;now when check “git status”, will see that the file had been marked in green color as shown in the below image.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/working_with_git/git_add.png&quot; alt=&quot;git add&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Then we need to commit the file for push using the following command.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;git commit -am “&amp;lt;Reason for changing the file&amp;gt;”
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Committing a file is necessary so that people will come to know why you changed the file. After successfully committing a file, when you check for “git status” you will see no error messages and so you file is ready to be pushed to the remote repository.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/working_with_git/git_commit.png&quot; alt=&quot;git commit&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For pushing a committed file to the remote repository type the following command in the terminal.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;git push origin master
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You will be asked with the username and password for push the file. After the your file will be pushed to repository.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/working_with_git/git_push.png&quot; alt=&quot;git push&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;And you can check the github repository for verification.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/working_with_git/changes_checked.png&quot; alt=&quot;git changes_checked&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now, we know some basics on how to work with git. In next part you will get to know things like branching, pull request and many other.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 29 Dec 2017 00:00:00 +0530</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:3000/blog/2017/Working-with-GIT/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:3000/blog/2017/Working-with-GIT/</guid>
        
        
        <category>Welcome</category>
        
        <category>Git</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Overview of Programming</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Seriously, I am not a die-hard programmer but I code for making my Algorithms works and I like it. In this era of digitalisation, learning programming is one of the priliminary one which helps one to absorb and understand the dynamically evolving world. Different people have different people reason for their interest in programming. In world of programming, there are several different programming languages and each have their own advantages and disadvantages. The typical 256 programming languages are mentioned in this &lt;a href=&quot;https://dzone.com/articles/big-list-256-programming&quot;&gt;Dzone Page&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you are interested in getting placed in some cool cooperates like Google, Facebook, Microsoft,.etc.. Then you must select one of the cool programming Language and practise it. People there in those cooperate doesn’t actually much care about what programming language you know but they make sure you are good with the following things (May be added with some):&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt; Problem Solving Ability &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt; Algorithm &amp;amp; Data Structures &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt; Experience on Programming &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As these points hadn’t scored any programming languages, that doesn’t mean you can select any programming language randomly and practise. Selecting a good programming language for your application is a critical one it indirectly places a major part in getting though some tough interviews. Just look at the pre-defined points for getting into some cool coperates, “Problem solving ability” totally independent on the type of programming languages, Whatever language you choose, its your mental training and focus that actual makes you good in this criteria. But remaining two mainly depends on the language you choose, you may read some 400 or 600 pages books on “Algorithm &amp;amp; Data Strutures” or separate books on each topics but what actually makes you good in this topics is directly applying it and that actually means you need a programming language that facilitates you in doing so and most particularly you should be comfortable with that language. Following that, to shine in “Experience on work” criteria who should really live a typical programmers life for atleast 6 months and several startups concerns will help you a lot in gathering more Experience on the field, in this context and as a founder of my own startup, I need to add that I am preparing a separate blog on “Learning from Startups”. And also don’t think getting into a startup is a easy task, you can’t join as a trainee in any startup and they don’t have both time and funds for supporting your learning. People in startups ask for coders having proficiency in a particularly language and yeah if you choose some poor language with less amount of application you can’t get any works even as a free lanchers and you can’t get a startup needing programmers in that language.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, If you want me to Recommend some best programming languages, Here are some of the languages I suggest. you can learn any one of this.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Javascript&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Python&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Java&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Swift&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Ruby&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I am going to describe more on each languages. Let me start from last, &lt;a href=&quot;&quot;&gt;RUBY&lt;/a&gt; is a simple and good but been popular maily because of its framework named &lt;a href=&quot;&quot;&gt;Ruby on Rails&lt;/a&gt; which is one of the best and cool framework for web development with lot of community support, if you have passion of becoming a good web developer(backend) probably this language is for you. Then comes SWIFT, favourite language for apple. This language is used create apps for both iphones and ipads. Swift developers are very rare and wanted by numerous startups and even by MNCs. There are good tutorials, documentations and communities available online which you can use in learning this, but don’t you need a Macbook for working on this language. Next, JAVA is one of the oldest and most accepted languages. There are several application of Java including Android. Even though there are more Java developers, still companies these expert in this in high demand. Here comes my favourite, PYTHON is one of the coolest and most used languages in world. Several Companies including python have most of their application written in python. When your are focused on Algorithms, Analytics, Science,..then Python is for you. Most of the programs in Machine Learning, Data Analytics are written Python. Python can also adapted for web development with the advent of two awesome framework name Django and Flask. Learning Python is made Simple with several Tutorials, documentations, Communities Supports,.etc.. There will be always oppurtunity for python developers in several areas. Atlast, JAVASCRIPT derived from Java is a awesome language from front-end Designers. It mostly run in client side making it more robust and reliable. Whatever website you crawl, Javascript plays a major part in that. Nowdays, Javascript is also being used for backend programming in the name of NodeJS.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Most people start their programming journey from &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/C_(programming_language)&quot;&gt;C Language&lt;/a&gt;, then followed with &lt;a href=&quot;&quot;&gt;C++&lt;/a&gt;. C++ will help us in understanding the fundamentals of Object Oriented Programming concept shortly known as OOPS. OOPS refined the possibilities of programming. Having OOPS as base several programming languages came into existence like JAVA, PYTHON, RUBY, GO,..etc. Each one has its own use cases and functionalities. As I told before that I am not a Die-Hard programmer and I have knowledge on programming in some limited domains, I can’t be more generic on this. My works are mostly in Python, Ruby, C++,..etc. Let me first project the domains I am familiar with and the programming concepts that will be covered in this post will be mostly from these domains.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt; Web-Development &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt; Data Analysis &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt; Machine Learning &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt; Shell scripting &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt; Deep Learning &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Let me start with Web-Development, world of web had seen many drastic changes in the last 5 year and is being updated dynamically in a daily. With the advent of open-source contribution, Different libraries and tools are been developed and maintained by several open source contributor.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 14 Dec 2017 00:00:00 +0530</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:3000/blog/2017/Overview-of-Programming/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:3000/blog/2017/Overview-of-Programming/</guid>
        
        
        <category>Coding</category>
        
        <category>General</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Introduction</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Hi there, Myself &lt;strong&gt;Murugesan&lt;/strong&gt;. Its kind of late start for me in writing blogs, after I left hands from my first blog. Before starting my first blog, I was like thinking that writing blog and maintaining blog will be a piece of cake. But after I encounter more time loss in my first blog, I left the hope on blogging. But now thinking that this is the correct time to start blogging my ideas, works, experience,..etc. Initially if you want to know about me, you can refer &lt;a href=&quot;https://murugeshmarvel.github.io/about/&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;. During my college day I explored lot in both technical and non-technical stuffs, some are pretty awesome to showcase and others won’t be that much interesting. After my college I worked and contributed for several AI startups and gathered new and exiting experience which I would also share in this blog.
This blog will contains many tutorials, experiments and other information related to the following stuffs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Programming&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Algorithms&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Artificial Intelligence&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Travelling &amp;amp; Exploring&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Entrepreneur's Guide&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Philosophy&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
and may be more.
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sat, 09 Dec 2017 00:00:00 +0530</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:3000/blog/2017/Introduction/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:3000/blog/2017/Introduction/</guid>
        
        
        <category>Welcome</category>
        
        <category>Personal</category>
        
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
